L'amore a vent'anni
Mattino, mi sveglio cantando
La sera, a letto ballando
Non mi preoccupo
Delle bombe in volo
Quel giorno ci uccideranno tutti
Non serve preoccuparsi!
Antoine Doinel oggi ha 20 anni.
I suoi scherzi dispettosi
lo hanno portato davanti al giudice.
Dopo aver abbandonato la sua casa, si sente libero.
Antoine ha organizzato, con cura, una sua vita indipendente.
Amante della musica,
lavora in una casa discografica.
Finalmente ha realizzato il suo sogno,
vivendo da solo con una paga,
camminando con i suoi piedi...
Icsritto in un music club per giovani
non perde mai un evento.
Riesce ad ottenere biglietti gratuiti per importanti concerti.
IL suo unico amico è René Biget,
un agente di borsa.
Come va il mercato azionario?
Bene. Presto diventerò un agente di cambio.
Sto andando in fabbrica.
Ho due biglietti per stasera, per Shapiro.
Ricordi quando ti nascondevi nella mia stanza e mio papà è entrato?
Quanto fumo!
Mio padre!
Aiutami a scuotere le coperte per togliere  il fumo!
Va bene, basta!
Ma cos'è? Un affumicatoio!
Sembra una bisca!
Bene, ti tratterrò tre sigari dalla tua paghetta.
Bucefalo non è un attaccapanni!
Ne vale migliaia!
È un'opera d'arte!
Non lo venderei mai.
Adesso state buoni e andate a letto!
Buona notte!
Mi aveva quasi scoperto!
Vide i tuoi piedi ma non disse nulla.
E ora di andare.
Non l'avevo mai notata. Mi piace veramente.
Molto! Come la sua amica?
Sarebbe perfetto!
Ho una storia con mia cugina.
Porta i capelli lunghi.
Vuole tagliarli. Grande!
L'ami?
Non saprei. Non ho detto nulla.
Se la preferisco con i capelli corti,
- Glielo scriverò.
- Dimmi come va...
8 GIORNI DOPO
L'ho vista tre volte la settimana scorsa.
Non le ho ancora parlato, ma si è accorta di me.
Giovedi' scorso all'Eroica,
Ero seduto dietro di lei.
Ha slacciato la sciarpa.
Le ho osservato il collo ed i capelli.
L'ho fissata per tutta la serata!
Ho deciso di parlarle e l'ho rincorsa ,
ma ha incontrato un'amica.
Sono tornato a casa... a dormire.
Giovedì, sono arrivato presto per sedermi accanto a lei.
Non c'era ancora nessuno,
cos' ho fumato una sigaretta
finchè la sala si è riempita.
Quando sono entrato, in un primo momento non l'ho vista.
Ma stava parlava con una amica.
Mi sono seduto accanto a lei.
Lei annuì come se mi conoscesse.
Ma lei andò a sedersi
dove aveva lasciato il suo cappotto!
Non ho osato cambiare posto.
The third time was yesterday.
She was carrying home her groceries,
in my neighbourhood!
The preliminaries are over. Attack!
What has Pierre Schaeffer taught us? A lot.
He's dealt musicology a staggering blow.
Clichy's my stop.
Odd I didn't see you sooner.
You go often?
Yes, to all the Russian concerts.
Sunday mornings.
Not much fun!
It's a shame,
but we'd have met sooner or later.
Don't I live near you?
I saw you with your shopping.
I live on Lécluse.
What do you do?
I'm a student. And you?
- I'm in records.
- You work?
For Philips.
I'm on my own.
It must be strange to be independent!
That depends, because...
It's my stepfather's car!
Going to the Gavoty lecture?
Probably.
If not, I'll surely be at the concert
the next night or the night after.
Okay, but what's your phone number?
I'll see you again, right?
Yes, but call in the evening.
I'm not always in.
It's Carnot 08-32.
Well, I've got work!
Goodnight. See you!
Antoine and Colette met often
and traded books and records.
Over lemonades, they discussed stereo,
and walked home
and talked for hours in doorways.
To her, he was a pal.
He didn't notice it, or else it pleased him.
Friends, this is the second discussion
of experimental music.
After the first one with Pierre Schaeffer,
I knew by your attentiveness
and from your numerous letters
how interested you were!
- Colette?
- Yes, it's me.
- My head aches!
- Where were you last night? Sick?
I only said "maybe"!
I went to a party with friends.
Really crazy people. We had a ball!
It was terrific but really crazy at the end.
I got home at 5:00 this morning!
Can I see you this afternoon?
I might be out. We all said
we'd meet again this afternoon.
Okay, see you later!
Come by if you want.
Is Colette in?
- No, why?
- I brought her books back.
- I'll take them.
- And this letter, too.
I'll give her everything.
- You're Antoine?
- Yes.
She's mentioned you often. Come in!
- Who is it?
- A friend of Colette's!
- Got a moment?
- I don't want to bother.
It's Antoine!
You're in her class?
They met at the youth concerts.
Colette told us!
Antoine works! In records, right?
Yes, for Philips.
Fine!
I think young folks
should go to work early in life.
I started at 15 at Labord's Garage.
Now I'm the boss!
I never drink.
Education's no help.
Take Victor Hugo!
Please! Never mind Victor Hugo!
He denounced evil, but didn't cure it.
Right?
Perhaps!
Well, I must go. Excuse me.
Going already? Colette will be sorry.
- Me, too!
- You must come to dinner soon!
I'll talk to Colette.
Your love letter was well-written,
it shows you're experienced!
Will you be at Leroux's tonight?
Thanks for the books.
Mother says you're romantic
because of your hair.
See you tonight. Colette.
- Look who I see!
- Antoine!
Just opposite us!
What's going on?
- You live there now?
- Yes.
- Since when?
- This afternoon.
Can we come up?
He's all settled in!
A washbasin! A telephone!
Come look out the window!
You can see our two windows!
But we get the sun.
Are your folks alive?
Yes, but I don't see them often. We fight.
That's a shame!
Your mama must miss you!
It's my fault.
At home, I ran away often.
- If only Colette would!
- Don't try me!
A family is...
Where is one better off
than with one's family? Anywhere!
- Hervé Bazin!
- Yes, in Viper in the Fist!
Colette may not look like it, but...
- François, pour!
- Incredible!
No respect any more!
Colette's parents liked young people
and soon adopted Antoine
and invited him often.
Antoine watched Colette come and go.
She treated him as before.
His move didn't deepen their friendship.
How are you?
What brings you by?
I got two seats for Gavoty
on electronic music.
No, I have a lot of work this afternoon.
How about a film?
I can't. I have an essay
that's due tomorrow.
- Can't we talk a while?
- No. Some other time. Bye!
What a schmuck!
I'm off to a bad start.
I shouldn't be in love with her.
She talks to me like a pal.
When I get serious, she laughs!
I wait hours for her till I'm frozen!
Well, I'll tell you about my cousin.
She cut her hair like Joan of Arc.
I love her and write to her.
Here's one from her!
Terrific!
And the envelope!
I'm in record manufacture now.
- Ice cream?
- No, thanks.
It's the first record I made. It's for you!
- That's nice!
- It took a long time!
Ice cream, chocolate, sweets
and caramels.
The French and Austrians
fought at the Auberon Slalom.
Charles Bozon finished
both heats and took second place
in front of Burger.
Adrien Duvillard finished fourth,
in front of Leitner
and his Austrian namesake.
The Swiss, Mathis,
who was winning in the first heat,
won the slalom
in two minutes, four seconds.
Once again, the Austrian
Zimmermann won the heat
and took second place,
which Schranz then stole...
I knocked for five minutes!
Are you deaf?
It's dark in here! Are you sick?
I wanna set things straight.
All these little games...
I can't stand it!
You're an idiot!
Sure, it's my fault.
I shouldn't have moved here.
I'm gonna move back where I was.
So don't lead me on!
- Leave me alone!
- What a bore!
But you're invited to dinner!
I won't go!
Never mind that. Come to dinner.
If you change your mind,
we'll eat in 15 minutes.
- Had dinner?
- Yes.
- Sure?
- Yes, thanks.
Really? I can make an omelette quickly!
I'll have a tangerine.
What's new?
Going out tonight?
I got two seats for Schwarzhof.
But I don't know.
- Go on!
- I can't!
Why?
Never you mind!
The Schwarzhof recital's on TV.
Want a plate?
No, don't bother.
Who is it?
It's a real procession.
This is Albert. I told you about him.
- You know Antoine.
- We met once.
I'll get my coat!
A cigarette, please.
I'm ready. We're off! So long!
Have a nice evening!
Let's watch that TV programme.
Could I have a light?
He has kindly made an exception for us.
He has admitted that...
They fall in love
all over the world!
All the youth of the world
bite into life
as if it were a big apple!
The first kiss!
Hello, sorrow!
Take my heart!
Give me your hand!
It goes wrong! It goes right!
Youth is so fleeting,
when two by two they go their way,
singing down the highway,
when you're 20 and in love!